Guide to the Charles Kent Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Charles Kent papers
1783-1910
OSB MSS 78
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.63
(6 boxes)
Series I, Correspondence, consists almost entirely of single letters to Charles Kent on professional and literary topics. Significant correspondents include E. L. Blanchard; F. C. Burnand, editor of Punch; E. M. Thompson; Laura Valentine; and Samuel Warren. The series also contains a letter from Lamartine praising Kent's poetry; Cardinal Manning's last letter to his mother; and copies of letters addressed to Kent from literary figures such as Charles Dickens, Robert Browning, and Lord Lytton. Series II, Writings, contains papers related to several of Kent's works, including page proofs for Leigh Hunt as Poet and Essayist and Poems (1870); preliminary materials for Corona Catholica; several leader articles for The Sun and the Weekly Register, including an obituary prepared in expectation of the death of the Prince of Wales in 1871; and holograph versions of several poems by Kent. Series III, Personal Papers, contains biographical and family papers; a journal kept by Kent during his travel to Rome in 1869; and a small quantity of memorabilia and other papers, including a document relating to hostage negotiations by the Paris Commune in 1870.
Kent, Charles, 1823-1902
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from John Hart on the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Fund, 1999.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile in box 7 may only be consulted with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies or photographic prints for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
CHARLES KENT, 1823-1902
Charles William Mark Kent was born in London on November 3, 1823. The eldest son of the Roman Catholic naval officer William Kent, he was educated at Prior Park, Bath and St. Mary's College, Oscott. In 1845 he succeeded William Frederick Deacon as editor of the liberal evening newspaper, The Sun, and in 1850 he purchased it from Murdo Young, whose daughter Ann he married in 1853.
He edited and published the newspaper until its failure in 1871. One of the first dailies to offer book reviews, many of which Kent wrote, The Sun offered frequent leading articles on the political issues of the day, also authored by him. Several of these, including "The Gladstone Government, by A Templar," were published separately under pseudonyms.
During his editorship, Kent also published several literary works, including Aletheia, or, The Doom of Mythology and Other Poems (1850); frequent contributions to Household Words and All the Year Round, both edited by his friend Charles Dickens; a poem welcoming Longfellow to England in 1868; and his collected Poems in 1870. In 1869 Kent attended the preliminary sessions of the Vatican I Ecumenical Council in Rome.
After the failure of The Sun, Kent devoted his time to editing the Weekly Register, a Roman Catholic journal, from 1874-1881, and to producing a series of biographies and editions devoted to English authors. These include The Works of Charles Lamb (1874), containing a memoir of his life with details supplied by the actress Frances Maria Kelly; The Wit and Wisdom of Lord Lytton (1883); The Humour and Pathos of Charles Dickens (1884); and Leigh Hunt as an Essayist (1888). In 1880 he published Corona Catholica, a work containing translations into 50 languages of an epigram on the accession of Leo XIII to the Papacy.
In 1887 Kent received a Civil List Pension, and in his final years contributed several articles to the Dictionary of National Biography. He and his wife had five sons and two daughters; two of the sons predeceased him. He died at his home in Campden Hill on February 23, 1902 and was buried in the Roman Catholic cemetary in Kensal Green.
Scope and Contents
The Charles Kent Papers consist of correspondence, writings, and personal papers documenting aspects of the professional and literary careers of the editor and author Charles Kent. The collection has been organized into three series: Series I, Correspondence; Series II, Writings, and Series III, Personal Papers. The papers span the dates 1783-1910, with the bulk of the material dating from between 1860 and 1900.
Series I, Correspondence, housed in Boxes 1-2, spans the years 1831- 1910 and is organized into three subseries: General Correspondence, Copies of Letters to Charles Kent, and Third-Party Correspondence. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
The first subseries, General Correspondence, consists mainly of single letters addressed to Kent on professional and literary matters. Topics include articles recently published or proposed; thanks for books sent by Kent; corrections to items that appeared in Kent's newspapers; and general personal news and expressions of shared Catholic faith. Letters with significant or unusual subject interest have been described more fully in the box and folder listing. Correspondents represented by more than two letters include E. L. Blanchard; F. C. Burnand, the editor of Punch; Sir Edward Maunde Thompson; the novelist Laura Valentine; C. J. Vaughan; and Samuel Warren.
The second subseries, Copies of Letters to Charles Kent, contains copies made by Kent of letters from figures including Charles Dickens, Wilkie Collins, and William Harrison Ainsworth.
The third subseries, Third-Party Correspondence, includes letters and evidence from Monsignor T. J. Capel concerning his dispute with Cardinal Manning in 1882-83; and Cardinal Manning's last letter to his mother before her death in 1847, with a note from him on the circumstances of the correspondence.
Series II, Writings, is housed in Box 3 and is organized into two subseries: Books and Pamphlets and Shorter Works. Shorter Works itself is further subdivided into into Articles, Poems, and Reviews. The papers span the dates 1847-1898 and consist primarily of production papers such as page proofs, ancillary material including advertisements, reviews and distribution lists, and, in the case of Poems, holographs or typescripts of indiviudal works.
The first subseries, Books and Pamphlets, is arranged alphabetically by title. Poems (1870 edition) and Leigh Hunt as Poet and Essayist are represented by page proofs in various states. Folder x contains a largely positive review of Kent's earliest collection of poems, the 1850 Aletheia.
There are twelve folders of papers documenting some of Kent's work on Corona Catholica, including various lists of potential and actual contributors and of the fifty languages in which the translations appeared; a folder of research notes on the Prophecy of St. Malachy concerning the future of the Papacy, which was referenced in the original Latin epigram; a holograph dummy of a projected layout for the collection; the text of Kent's dedicatory preface in English and Latin; and reviews and announcements.
Other material in the subseries includes sales figures for The Life of Charles Lamb and a few papers relating to Kent's projected collection of translations of hymns from the Roman Breviary.
The second subseries, Shorter Works, largely contains holographs, typescripts and printed versions of brief works by Kent. Among these are a proof printing of an obituary for Albert Edward, Prince of Wales, whose death was expected at the time Kent composed it; a holograph draft of an article on Edgar Allen Poe, accompanied by a rejection letter from Blackwood's; and a typescript of an article on Kent's experiences among the artists and writers of Chelsea in the 1870s and 1880s. There are also holograph copies of several poems composed during Kent's European travels in 1869, including "The Judgement of St. Gudule" and "Salome," on a visit to the studio of William Wetmore Story.
Series III, Personal Papers, spans the dates 1783-1902 and is organized into eight alphabetically arranged subseries: Artwork; Biographical Information; Family Papers; Journals and Notebooks; Photographs; Printed Material; and Research Material.
The subseries Biographical Information contains papers documenting Kent's education, work, club memberships, and marriage to Ann Young Kent, including a few items related to her own creative writing. Family Papers contains several items connected to the naval career of Captain William Kent, including his commission as Fourth Lieutenant of the Blenheim, an account of stock, and a promissory note for Calcutta rupees; and other papers, such as genealogical notes and a copy of the marriage certificate of Kent's father-in-law, Murdo Young.
The subseries Journals and Notebooks contains a daily diary with routine entries from 1892; several small memorandum books, undated; and Kent's "Journal of a Six Week Tour," written during his 1869 travels to attend the opening of Vatican I. In addition to sightseeing descriptions and transportation details, the journal contains lengthy accounts of conversations with fellow journalists in most of the major European cities; his contacts with Cardinal Manning and William Wetmore Story in Rome; and visits in Florence with the sculptor Charles Fuller and the novelist T. A. Trollope.
Memorabilia and Other Papers is housed in folders xx-xx and consists largely of items kept by Kent as souvenirs. These include Thomas Moore's letter of admission to the Inner Temple; a petition for the relief of Lamb's friend, the actress Francis Maria Kelly; scraps of music saved from the 1865 Covent Garden Theater fire; and a document relating to negotiations between the Paris Commune and the Thiers forces for the exchange of Georges Darboy, Archbishop of Paris and Louis Blanqui, dated two weeks before the Archbishop was shot at Roquette.
The subseries Printed Material includes holy cards collected by Kent; advertisements, calling cards, and newspaper clippings, including four folders on the death of Benjamin Disraeli, Lord Beaconfield. Photographs contains a view of the first cathedral built at Lourdes, autographed by the parish priest to whom Bernadette Soubouris confided her visions
Material housed in other subseries includes a caricature by E. L. Blanchard, a silhouette portrait, and a watercolor of the Vatican coat of arms in Artwork; and research notes and library call slips in Research Materials.
Oversize material is housed in Box 6 in series order.
Catholics -- England; English literature -- 19th century; English poetry -- 19th century; Journalism -- Great Britain; Newspaper publishing -- England -- London; Periodicals -- England; Europe -- Description and travel; Paris (France) -- History -- Commune, 1871; Authors; Journalists; Edward, King of Great Britain, VII, 1841-1910; Leo, Pope, XIII, 1810-1903; Blanchard, E. L. (Edward L.), 1820-1889; Browning, Robert, 1812-1889; Burnand, F. C. (Francis Cowley), 1836-1917; Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870; Hunt, Leigh, 1784-1859; Kent, Charles, 1823-1902; Lamartine, Alphonse de, 1790-1869; Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron, 1803-1873; Manning, Henry Edward, 1808-1892; Thompson, Edward Maunde, Sir, 1840-1929; Valentine, L. (Laura), 1814-1899; Warren, Samuel, 1807-1877; Catholic Church -- England; Vatican Council (1st) ( 1869-1870 Basilica di San Pietro in Vaticano)
- Correspondence, 1815-1918; Series I; 0.81; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is organized into three subseries, all of which are alphabetically arranged by correspondent.
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Aird, ----
      - ALS to CK; 340 The Strand, 1873 Feb 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Allen, J.
      - ALS to CK; Morning Post, 1871 Oct 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        With envelope. With notes.
    - Arnold, Mary Jane
      - ALS to CK; 31 Colville Square, 1875 Jun 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Thanking him for review. With envelope.
    - Athenaeum Club (London, England). Library
      - Letter of acknowledgement to CK, 1900 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Balfour, Betty, Lady, b. 1867
      - 3 ALS to CK, 1890-98 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Family news and thanks for gifts. With envelopes.
    - Balfour, W. G.
      - ALS to CK; 24 Addison Road, [1895 Jan 8] (Box 1, Folder 6)
        With envelope.
    - Bancroft, Squire, 1841-1926
      - ALS to CK; Kursall Maloja, 1898 Aug 22 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bentley, Richard, 1794-1871
      - ALS to CK; New Burlington Street, 1866 Apr 26 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Asking for a copy of Kent's poem "on the Lord Protector." With envelope.
    - Blackmore, John, 1815-1890
      - ALS to CK; 3 Randolph Crescent, Edinburgh, 1866 Apr 15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        Concerning an article by him. With envelope.
    - Blackwood, John, 1832-
      - Letter copy to CK, 1871 May (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Concerning literary matters
    - Blanchard, E. L. (Edward L.), 1820-1889
      - 7 ALS to CK, 1842-43, 1875, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
        Concerning literary matters, including an attack on Dickens and the state of London journalism. With two playbills for "The Road of Life," n.d. With envelopes.
    - Bliss, Constance
      - ALS to CK; British Embassy, Paris, 1891 Nov 30 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Concerning the death of her father. With envelope.
    - Braddon, M. E. (Mary Elizabeth), 1837-1915
      - ALS to CK; 24 Cheyne Walk, n.y. Apr 26 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        Thanks for and appreciation of a gift of Kent's Poems. With envelope.
    - Brain, Earnest
      - TLS to CK; Savage Club, 1898 Jun 30 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        Condolences for the death of Kent's son.
    - Brandt, Julius G.
      - ALS to CK; Hotel de Paris, 1854 Jan 29 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Brown, Ford Madox, 1821-1893
      - ALS to CK; 14 Grove Terrace, 1865 Mar 30 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Thanking him for a highly favorable review. With envelope.
    - Browning, Robert, 1812-1889
      - Letter copy to CK, 1884 Mar 31 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        Thanking him for a copy of his book and sympathizing with "the calamity that has befallen you." With: copy of presentation inscription from Browning to Kent.
    - Bryant, C. H.
      - ALS to CK; Norfolk House, 1900 Jul 5 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bulwer, Elizabeth Barbara
      - ALS to CK; Hufdon, [1879 Mar 19] (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bunn, A. (Alfred), 1796?-1860
      - ALS to CK, 1851 Jan (Box 1, Folder 22)
        With envelopes.
    - Burnand, F. C. (Francis Cowley), Sir, 1836-1917
      - 12 ALS to CK, 1877-81, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
        Subjects include "Punch," literary news, and questions involving Roman Catholicism. Eight with envelopes.
    - Carpenter, William, 1797-1874
      - ALS to CK; 5 Euston Square, 1870 Oct 20 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        With envelope. With newspaper clipping, 1870 Oct 20, discussing a pamphlet by Carpenter.
    - Cassidy, F.
      - ALS to CK; Beaumont College, 1883 Feb 5 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Chamberlain, Joseph, 1836-1914
      - ALS to E. Kent; House of Commons, 1902 Feb 28 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        Condolences on death of CK. With envelope.
    - Corelli, Marie, 1855-1924
      - Letter copy to CK, 1886 Mar 16 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        Concerning reception of her first novel, A Romance of Two Worlds
    - Collins, Wilkie, 1824-1889
      - Letter copy to CK, 1873 Jul 12 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Courtney, Thomas
      - ALS to CK; Athenaeum Club, 1901 Mar 26 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Crossley, Francis William, 1839-1897
      - ALS to CK; Falcon Hall, 1867 Oct 23 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Daly, H. L.?
      - ALS to CK, n.y. Nov 18 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Darnley, John Stuart Bligh, Earl of, 1827-1896
      - ALS to CK; Cobham Hall, 1867 Oct 26 (Box 1, Folder 33)
        Declining to attend dinner in honor of Dickens. With envelope.
    - De Vere, Aubrey, 1814-1902
      - ALS to CK; Athenaeum, 1881 Jun 21 (Box 1, Folder 34)
        Concerning club membership. With envelope.
    - Dobell, Sydney, 1824-1874
      - ALS to CK, 1861 Apr 2 (Box 1, Folder 35)
        Concerning literary matters and journalism; recommending the work of R. W. Buchanan With envelope.
    - Dunn, J.
      - Telegram to CK, [1892 Nov 4] (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Evill, H.
      - ALS to CK; 1 Lancaster Gate, 1901 Dec 12 (Box 1, Folder 37)
        Sending present of wine. With envelope.
    - Evill, William
      - ALS to CK; 2 Elm Terrace, 1848 Sep 7 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Fields, James Thomas, 1817-1881
      - AL draft from CK to Fields, 1873 Sep 1 (Box 1, Folder 39)
        With annotated envelope.
    - Gordon, Taylor
      - ALS to CK; Alfred House, 1852 Dec 31 (Box 1, Folder 40)
        On recent political developments.
    - Grove, George, Sir, 1820-1900
      - 2 ALS to CK; Lower Sydenham, 1886 May, Jun (Box 1, Folder 41)
        Thanking him for his book and sending condolences. With envelopes.
    - Hamley, E. B., Colonel
      - ALS to CK, 1867 Nov 5 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Hart, Horace, 1840-1916
      - TLS to Mrs. Charles Kent; Oxford University Press, 1901 Mar 8 (Box 1, Folder 43)
        Concerning CK's health and Latin translations.
    - Howard, Mary A. F.
      - ALS to CK; Norfolk House, 1900 Jun 24 (Box 1, Folder 44)
        Asking him to call tomorrow. With envelope.
    - Hudson, Daniel E.
      - ALS to Mrs. Charles Kent; Notre Dame, Indiana, 1901 Apr 1 (Box 1, Folder 45)
        Concerning contributions to the "Ave Maria" and CK's health.
      - Envelope addressed to CK, 1901 Apr 8 (Box 1, Folder 46)
        Containing blank Easter card and several printed copies of a translation of "Antiphons of the Blessed Virgin" by CK
    - Hunt, Leigh, 1784-1859
      - Copies of two letters to CK, 1847 and 1858 (Box 1, Folder 47)
        Thanking him for favorable reviews
    - Ireland, Alexander, 1810-1894
      - ALS to [CK]; Inglewood, Cheshire, 1877 Mar 24 (Box 1, Folder 48)
        Concerning bibliographical corrections for an article about Charles Cowden Clarke
    - Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905
      - 2 telegrams to CK, 1899, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Jerrold, Blanchard, 1826-1884
      - ALS to CK, 1870, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 50)
        With copy of "In remembrance of the late Mr. Douglas Jerrold" in CK's hand, n.d. With envelopes.
    - Kent, William
      - 3 ALS to CK, 1876-98 (Box 1, Folder 51)
        Personal news to his "Papa." With 2 envelopes.
    - Lamartine, Alphonse de, 1790-1869
      - ALS to CK; Paris, 1863 Apr 9 (Box 1, Folder 52)
        Praising CK's poem "Aletheia." In French.
    - Lawlor, Denys-Shyne
      - ALS to CK, 1870 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 53)
        Concerning article on pilgrimages in the Pyrenees (Lourdes). With envelope.
    - Liddell, Richard
      - 2 ALS to CK, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 54)
        With autograph manuscript of a "Leader" article. With envelope.
    - Lucas, E. V. (Edward Verrall), 1868-1938
      - TLS to Mrs. Charles Kent; 86 Great Portland Street, 1901 oct 19 (Box 1, Folder 55)
        Concerning CK's health and an excerpt from one of his works. With envelope.
    - Lytton, Edith Villiers Bulwer-Lytton, Countess, 1841-1936
      - ALS to CK; Knowsley, 1895 Jan 4 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Lytton, Edward Robert Bulwer-Lytton, Earl of, 1831-1891
      - Telegram to CK, 1883 Aug 27 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Mackay, Minnie
      - ALS to CK; 41 Kensington Gardens, Bayswater, [n.y. May 29] (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Mackenzie, R. Shelton (Robert Shelton), 1809-1880
      - ALS to CK; Manchester, 1852 Feb 7 (Box 1, Folder 59)
        Concerning autographs. With envelope.
    - Matthews, C. J.
      - Letter copy to CK, 1861 Nov 28 (Box 1, Folder 60)
        Thanking him for a favorable review
    - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852
      - 2 copies of letter to CK, 1847 Jun 22 (Box 1, Folder 61)
        Addressing Kent as a "brother Catholic" and praising his pamphlet. With envelope.
    - Nicholson, E. W. B. (Edward Williams Byron), 1849-1912
      - ALS to CK, 1901 Mar 23 (Box 1, Folder 62)
        Concerning Kent's donation to the Bodleian. With envelope.
    - Norfolk, Henry Fitzalan, Duke of, 1847-1917
      - 2 ALS to CK, 1873, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 63)
        With: copy of letter from Kent to Norfolk applying for a post in the Herald's College, 1873 Nov 14; With: TL carbon of letter from Norfolk to G. Crewe Orlebar, 1899 Aug 15 With envelope.
    - Oakely, F.
      - ALS to CK; 39 Duncan Terrace, 1878 Jun 21 (Box 1, Folder 64)
        Comments on Kent's Latin verses
    - Penny, William, 1809-1892
      - 2 ALS to CK, 1852 Mar, Apr (Box 1, Folder 65)
        Thanking CK for his defense. With envelope.
    - Plumptre, Charles John, 1818-1887
      - ALS to CK; 36 Hamilton Terrace, 1870 Mar 7 (Box 1, Folder 66)
        Thanking CK for a favorable review
    - Reid, Mayne, 1818-1883
      - 2 ALS to CK, 1861 Nov 27, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 67)
        Concerning political articles. With envelope.
    - Richards, A. B. (Alfred Bate), 1820-1876
      - ALS to CK; 44 Great Rupert St., 1867 Dec 4 (Box 1, Folder 68)
        Concerning literary matters and a recently published work of his. With envelope.
    - Robillard, J. S.
      - ALS to CK; Brandon, Manitoba, 1886 Jan 25 (Box 1, Folder 69)
        Describing his life as a missionary priest and the grave of Mark Kent, who died there in 1883 at the age of 21. With envelope annotated: "Dear Fr. Robillard's letter."
    - Rossetti, William Michael, 1829-1919
      - Letter copy to CK, n.y. Apr 23 (Box 1, Folder 70)
        Concerning the poetry of Whitman
    - Routledge, Robert
      - ALS to CK; Broadway, Ludgate Hill, London, 1894 Aug 21 (Box 1, Folder 71)
        With TLS carbon of letter from Kent to George Routledge and Sons, 1894 Aug 14. With envelope.
    - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900
      - Letter copy to CK, 1867 Nov 1 (Box 2, Folder 72)
        Thanking him for article
    - Saraiva, [Antonio Ribeiro], 1800-1890
      - ALS to CK; 21 Nottingham Street, Marylebone, 1851 Sep 19 (Box 2, Folder 73)
        Concerning Don Miguel and the Portuguese monarchy. With envelope.
    - Scott, J.
      - ALS to CK; 13 Edwardes Square, 1894 Sep 4 (Box 2, Folder 74)
        Note illustrated with sketch of artist in studio at easel. With envelope.
    - Spiers, William
      - ALS to CK; Ada Villa, Poona, 1880 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 75)
        Sending copy of the "Bombay Catholic Examiner"
        Related Archival Materials note
        See also: Oversize, Box 6, folder 232
    - Strutt, George
      - ALS to CK; Bridgehill, 1882 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 76)
        Concerning illustrations in Kent's tribute to Bulwer-Lytton. With envelope.
    - Talbot, Edward
      - ALS to CK; House of Commons, 1901 Feb 15 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Thompson, Edward Maunde, Sir, 1840-1929
      - 4 ALS to CK, 1899-1901 (Box 2, Folder 78)
        Three acknowledgement letters from the British Museum and a note setting an appointment. With acknowledgement letter from the Department of Printed Books, 1901 May 19. With envelopes.
    - Timbs, John, 1801-1875
      - ALS to CK; Seymour Cottage, 1867 Dec 21 (Box 2, Folder 79)
        Thanking him for favorable review
    - Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
      - ALS to CK; Hind Head House, Haslemere, 1889 Oct 17 (Box 2, Folder 80)
        Thanking him for volume. With envelope.
    - Valentine, L. (Laura), d. 1899
      - 3 ALS to CK, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 81)
        Concerning literary matters; thanking him for a favorable review and praising his poetry. With envelopes.
    - Vaughan, C. J. (Charles John), 1816-1897
      - 3 ALS to CK, 1875-81 (Box 2, Folder 82)
        Praising Kent's work; supporting his election to the Athenaeum Club. With calling card of Monsignior Rufo Scilla. With envelope.
    - Warren, Samuel, 1807-1877
      - 5 ALS to CK, 1848-58 (Box 2, Folder 83-84)
        Concerning literary matters and reviews of his works. With envelopes.
    - Wilkinson, E.
      - ALS to CK; 2 Vicarage Terrace, Burnham, [1868] May 30 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Wilson, J.
      - ALS to CK, 1901 Feb 25 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Unidentified correspondents